#### Contact

Imocchegiani@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ leandromocchegiani (LinkedIn) leandromocchegiani.com (Personal)

# Languages

English

Italian

Catalan

Spanish

## Certifications

IBM Cloud Essentials
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure
Foundations 2020 Certified
Associate

**Cloud Core** 

IBM Certified Advocate - Cloud v1

#### Honors-Awards

Winner of the Telefónica Open Future Crowdworking La Catedral contest

JWEF +INNOVACTION 2015 E4E Winner best Startup Finalist competition Naves 2016 Winner INCUBA Tecnológico 2017

# Leandro E. Mocchegiani

Digital Innovation Consultor Argentina

# Extracto

I have been a technological entrepreneur since I was 18 years old. I have found a tech startup. I'm a senior electronics technician and audiovisual designer. I'm currently studying for a postgraduate degree in innovation and technology management.

I'm working as a Business Architect in the Public Sector for Latin America at Oracle, specializing in Smart City. I lead a project called: City Solutions Palette with several colleagues from Latin America. I'm also an ambassador for the Oracle for Startup program. I'm a U4SSC member working on "integrated city solutions". I teach entrepreneurship and innovation. I tutor in several technology startups.

I lived for 4 years in Europe. I worked for the main technological leaders such as Vodafone, IBM, and Telefónica (Movistar). I collaborate with a social impact project that helps more than one hundred children from a very poor neighborhood to obtain better opportunities. Do you want to collaborate?

# Experience

IBM

Enterprise Solutions Architect IBM Consulting June 2021 - Present (9 months) Buenos Aires

I work in the IBM Consulting team for a large multinational banking client: ICBC (Industrial and Commercial Bank of China). Helping cover their technological, business, and architectural requirements. Specifically developing a new digital channel segment.

Some responsibilities include leading the business approach with a focus on technology architecture. Work providing architecture definitions to the IT team and the agile team cells. Provide market research with innovative approaches to reduce barriers to the adoption of new technologies and integrate legacy systems. Share experiences and implementation methods in the real world. Participate in the development and architecture of the business strategy.

#### **SURTANK**

Digital Innovation

September 2015 - Present (6 years 6 months) CABA.

With Surtank I provide training in innovation, technology, agile methodologies, digital marketing, and sales, mentoring, tech talks to organizations and startups. I give webinars, bootcamps and workshops.

A few programs I was ennvolved:

Academia Argentina Emprende (United Nations UNDP program)

Crédito Fiscal (Comisión de investigaciones científicas de la Prov de Buenos

Aires).

Workshop in "Emprende Day" and "Marketing Digital Experience at the University of Belgrano".

Academic Facilitator at # VosLoHacés / Subte Emprende / Argentina 2030 / Lean Startup Motion INDUSTRIES 4.0. among others.

#### U4SSC

U4SSC Member

July 2020 - Present (1 año 8 meses) Ginebra, Suiza

I'm working in the thematic group "Integrated City Solutions" thinking the future scenarios for city platforms. The "United for Smart Sustainable Cities" (U4SSC) is a UN initiative coordinated by ITU, UNECE, and UNHabitat, and supported by CBD, ECLAC, FAO, UNDP, UNECA, UNESCO, UNEP, UNEP-FI, UNFCCC, UNIDO, UNOP, UNU-EGOV, UN-Women and WMO to achieve Sustainable Development Goal 11: "Make cities and human settlements inclusive, safe, resilient and sustainable".

#### Oracle

2 years 3 months

Business Architect Applications Public Sector LAD agosto de 2020 - junio de 2021 (11 meses) CABA

I work with the APP's PS teamwork for all Latin American Countries with our biggest customers in government understanding their business and organizations needs and developing innovation, technological solutions, and roadmap to adopt best practices.

Specific responsibilities include Lead Business approach and Blueprint sessions with customers (processes, Information, technology). Deliver agile workshops and hackathons for digital transformations, adopt roadmaps,

optimization, and standardization strategies. Provide innovative approaches to lower barriers to the adoption of new technologies. Sharing Real World implementation experiences & methods. Participate in the development and execution of the Business strategy.

Architect HUB Public Sector LAD April 2020 - August 2020 (5 meses) CABA

I work with the HUB teamwork for all Latinoamerican Countries with our biggest customers in government understanding their needs and developing technological solutions and roadmap to adopt best practices.

Specific responsibilities include Lead Architecture and Blueprint sessions with customers (processes, Information, technology). Deliver agile workshops and hackathons for digital transformations, adopt roadmaps, optimization, and standardization strategies. Provide innovative approaches to lower barriers to the adoption of new technologies. Sharing Real World implementation experiences & methods. Participate in the development and execution of the IT strategy.

Architect Public Sector April 2019 - April 2020 (1 año 1 mes)

I am an Architect in the Public Sector (Argentina, Bolivia, Uruguay, and Paraguay). This teamwork with our biggest customers in government understanding their needs and developing technological solutions and roadmap to adopt best practices.

Municipalidad de Tres de Febrero Director of Entrepreneurs December 2018 - April 2019 (5 months) Gran Buenos Aires, Arg

Within the Secretary of Economic Development, my role was to coordinate all the resources and public policies for the development of the entrepreneurial ecosystem in Tres de Febrero. Together with the Directorates of Labor, Industry, and Commerce, we work together to achieve the goals of local economic development.

Parkool CEO and Founder noviembre de 2015 - diciembre de 2018 (3 años 2 meses) Buenos Aires CEO & Founder Parkool.

First Smart Parking Startup in Latin America where we help find and pay for all kinds of places to park. Creation, design, and implementation of the project.

Lema de Oro CSO and Partner March 2006 - May 2015 (9 years 3 months) Martinez, Buenos Aires.

Company dedicated wholesale meat industry. Creation of custom software for comprehensive sales management and start-up of the computerization of the entire production and operational system. Team building, attracting large clients, operations throughout the country. Deployment of the network of retail outlets.

#### Vodafone

Sales Manager and Product Tester
October 2004 - January 2006 (1 year 4 months) Barcelona, Spain

Was part of the team that participated in the launch of the NEW CONCEPT stores. The first own stores (they were not resellers) of the largest mobile phone company in the world. It was a successful pilot that was replicated in other parts of the world and offered levels of customer service quality and sales volume never before achieved by any other telecommunications company in Spain. Testing and evaluation of new products for Nokia, Samsung, BlackBerry, Sony Ericsson, etc. I was part of the first team in Europe to test and evaluate mobile video conferencing and 3G (UMTS) and the first UMTS modem network for notebooks. Within the company in 2005 I was the promoter of the world's first contest for short films made by mobile, which positioned the brand in a new market niche: "audiovisual content creators."

Neo Vision Producciones
CTO & Founder
August 2000 - January 2006 (5 years 6 months) Barcelona, Spain
Producer of Digital and Audiovisual content

Realization of creation of scenarios in VR (virtual reality), 3D Design, web pages, Advertising Spot, Contents, Institutional and Short Films.

# Telephone

Fiber Optic Technician

March 2004 - June 2004 (4 months) Barcelona, Spain

Temporary contract for the cabling and tuning of the fiber optic network for the U

#### **IBM**

#### Technician

August 1997 - December 1997 (5 months)

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Intern as a repair technician of low and medium voltage switching sources.

Repair of monitors and PC supplies .

Practice carried out at the end of the sixth year of high school.

# Education

Universidad Nacional de Tres de Febrero

Postgraduate in Innovation and Technology Management, GTEC  $\cdot$  (2019 - 2020) Tesis PENDING

Universidad UTN

Diploma in Open Innovation. Current

#### IAE Business School

Competence Ships, Training in Entrepreneurship (2016 - 2016)

### Ministry of Education and Science of Spain

Higher Technician in Development of Electronic

Products, Informatics · (2003 - 2003)

#### Oracle Sales Academy

OSPA Solution Engineering Training, Information

Technology (2019 - 2019)

#### IAE Business School

Value generation, integration and collaboration., Business · (2019 - 2019)